Are you tired of feeling like your baby is stuck in a sleep regression nightmare?
You read not alone.
Every four months.
Babies go through a major sleep regression that can leave parents exhausted and wondering what to do next.
But don't worry, we've got five proven tips to help you navigate this challenging time with your little one.
So let's dive in, roll, typing on a keyboard tip one, establish a bedtime routine to create a calming pre-sleep routine
that includes activities like bath time, reading and singing.
This helps signal to your babby that it's time for sleep.
Stick toe the same routine every night, even on weekends or during vacations.
Consistency is key when it comes to helping your baby develop healthy sleep habits.
Broll, a parent putting their baby in bed tip two.
Watch for sleepy cues pay attention to your baby's sleepy cues such as yawning, rubbing their eyes or becoming less active.
When you notice these cues, it's time to put your baby to bed.
Don't wait until they re-overtired, as this can make it harder for them to fall asleep and stay asleep.
Broll, a parent monitoring their babies.
Sleep patterns on a monitor tip three, create a sleep conducive environment, make sure the room is dark, quiet and at a comfortable temperature.
Consider using white noise machines or a fan to block out any background noise.
Invest in black-out curtains or shades to keep the room dark, which can help regulate your baby's circadian or hyphens.
Broll, a parent placing their baby in a darkened room tip four.
Avoid overstimulation, avoid stimulating activities or exposing your babby to bright lights and loud noises close to bedtime.
Try to win down before bed with relaxing activities like reading, singing or giving a gentle message.
This can help signal to your babby that it's time for sleep.
Broll, a parent giving their babby a gentle message tip five.
Be consistent stick to the same sleep schedule and bedtime routine every night, even on weekends or during vacations.
Consistency is key when it comes to helping your baby develop healthy sleep habits.
Avoid taking naps with your baby as this can confuse them about what time they should be sleeping.
Broll, a parent checking their baby's schedule on a notebook so there you have it five proven tips to help you navigate the four month sleep regression with your baby.
Remember, every baby is different so it may take some trial and error to find what works best for your little one.
But don't worry with patience, consistency and the right strategies.
You can help your baby develop healthy sleep habits that will last a lifetime.
And if you need more tips or advice, be sure to subscribe to our channel for more helpful content.
Broll, a subscribe button appears on screen thanks for watching and we'll see you in the next video.